<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0">
<channel>
	<title>Motions Recently Popular with MPs</title>
	<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/</link>
	<description>Monitor the Early Day Motions which have recently been most popular with MPs</description>
	<language>en-gb</language>
	<pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2010 07:02:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<ttl>20</ttl>
		<item>
			<title>Sustainable Communities Act 2007 (Amendment) Bill </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1095.htm</link>
			<description>That this House congratulates the Secretary of State for Communities and Local Government, the right hon. Member for Southampton, Itchen, and the Minister for Communities, the hon. Member for Stevenage, for their wholehearted support for the Sustainable Communities Act 2007 (Amendment) Bill; notes that the Bill had the support of the Official Opposition and the Liberal Democrats; hopes that the Bill will pass through this House in this Session; and therefore calls on the Government to ensure that the Bill is brought before this House before the end of this Parliament and, if necessary, included in negotiations over wash-up arrangements.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1095.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Earth Hour 2010 Campaign And The Palace Of Westminster </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1045.htm</link>
			<description>That this House supports WWF's Earth Hour 2010; notes the event's record of persuading one billion people worldwide to sign up to switch off their lights for an hour at 8.30 pm on 27 March 2010; congratulates those individuals, organisations, businesses and local authorities which have already pledged to take part; further notes that many British landmarks, including Canary Wharf, Piccadilly Circus, Trafalgar Square and the London Eye will switch their lights off; and calls on the House authorities to ensure that the Palace of Westminster and all other buildings on the Parliamentary estate take part by switching off external floodlights and non-essential internal lighting.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1045.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Treatment Of Christians And Religious Liberty </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/877.htm</link>
			<description>That this House notes with concern evidence that the persecution of Christians is increasing around the world; welcomes the current initiative to highlight this in churches across the country on Maundy Thursday; and urges the Government to do all it can to raise and pursue concerns about human rights and religious liberty in overseas countries through the Foreign and Commonwealth Office, the Department for Business, Innovation and Skills and the Department for International Development.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2010 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/877.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Lives On The Line Campaign </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1022.htm</link>
			<description>That this House recognises the bravery, dedication and sacrifice of members of the armed forces in Afghanistan and Iraq; applauds the recent review and enhancement of the Armed Forces' Compensation Scheme; and calls on the Government to amend the qualifying date of 6 April 2005 to 1 January 2001, which marks the beginning of the war on terror, that ensures equality of treatment for personnel injured in Iraq and Afghanistan and thereby honours its duty of care to this loyal and dignified group of service men and women and their families.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2010 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1022.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Debt Relief (Developing Countries) Bill </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1085.htm</link>
			<description>That this House supports the proposals in the Debt Relief (Developing Countries) Bill to stop vulture funds profiteering from the debts of heavily indebted poor countries; and calls for Government time to be allocated for the remaining stages of the Bill on 18 March 2010.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2010 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1085.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Conduct Of The Hon. Member For Christchurch </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1096.htm</link>
			<description>That this House regrets the actions taken by the hon. Member for Christchurch in objecting to further proceedings on the Sustainable Communities Act 2007 (Amendment) Bill; notes that a majority of hon. Members, the Government, the Official Opposition and the Liberal Democrats have declared support for the Bill; and calls on the hon. Member to withdraw his opposition to the Bill.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1096.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Michael Foot (No. 2) </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1029.htm</link>
			<description>That this House notes with sadness the passing of Michael Foot, the former hon. Member for Plymouth, Devonport and right hon. Member for Ebbw Vale and Blaenau Gwent; regards him as one of the outstanding parliamentarians of his era; and calls on the House authorities to find a way to recognise the enormous contribution of this extraordinary parliamentarian.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2010 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1029.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Dog Eating In The Philippines </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/774.htm</link>
			<description>That this House congratulates His Excellency Mr Antonio Lagdameo on his appointment as Ambassador of the Republic of the Philippines to the Court of St. James; notes the historic special relationship between the United Kingdom and the Republic of the Philippines and the never to be forgotten heroism shown by our Filipino allies during World War II; further notes the shared value of respect to the treatment of animals in both countries as evidenced by recent legislation in the Philippines providing severe penalties for those convicted of involvement in the dog meat trade; respectfully requests that Mr Lagdameo conveys to his government the hope of this House that a Special Filipino Task Force is created to enforce these laws thereby eliminating this cruel exploitation of animals once and for all; and calls on the Government to offer support and advice to ensure that the practice is finally stamped out.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2010 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/774.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Muslims In Britain </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1079.htm</link>
			<description>That this House opposes the increased demonisation of Muslims in sections of the media; expresses its deep concern at the recent visit to the House of Lords by the far-right politician Geert Wilders; condemns the English Defence League demonstration outside Parliament in support of Geert Wilders and its slogans and placards inciting hatred, such as its demand for the closure of the East London Mosque, that will only lead to a climate of fear, division and disharmony; welcomes the participation and contribution of Muslims in British society, including in politics; and believes that the full participation of all communities in the forthcoming general election is in the interests of democracy.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2010 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1079.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rank And Pension Of Soldiers Killed On Active Service </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1053.htm</link>
			<description>That this House, convinced that the courage and devotion to duty of members of the British armed forces who are killed while on active service for their country should be recognised and rewarded in every possible way, particularly by the pensions and help given to the families they leave behind, recommends that the Ministry of Defence's rule providing that pensions on promotion are payable only after the role for the new rank has been held for a year should be revoked for those killed in the service of their country, so that their families are paid the rate appropriate to the rank held at the time of death; and considers that the family of Sergeant Matthew Telford of Grimsby, promoted to the rank in June 2009 but killed by an assassin in Afghanistan in November of that year, along with Guardsman Jimmy Major of Cleethorpes and three other soldiers, should be paid the full pension appropriate to the rank he was proud to honour at the time of his death.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2010 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1053.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Unite's Not-For-profit Campaign </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1038.htm</link>
			<description>That this House recognises that the workforce in the not-for-profit sector plays a vital role in the delivery of services; believes that it is highly dedicated to the quality of care and provision for users and that its skills and professionalism must not be undermined by the decisions of commissioners; further believes that poor contracts are causing excessive overtime in order to maintain services resulting in high levels of stress, family breakdown, ill health and a poor working environment, including workplace bullying and a lack of duty of care; further believes that short term funding only leads to job insecurity, poor pension opportunities and the inability to plan and to be strategic; further believes that cuts in funding have led to a poorly trained and developed workforce; congratulates Unite's campaign to ensure that the needs of the not-for-profit workforce is not forgotten; and calls on the Government, local authorities and other funders to ensure that contracts are properly funded on the principle of best value and not low cost, to ensure that the funding period is extended to between five and 10 years, and to take urgent measures to support the workforce.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2010 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1038.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Gmb Union And Safeguard Campaign </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1015.htm</link>
			<description>That this House congratulates the GMB union on the launch of its national SafeGuard campaign to protect security guards from the risk of abuse and violence; notes that GMB members working as security guards report an increase in the number of violent attacks that they experience whilst going about their duties at work; further notes that no information is collected by the industry or its trade association, the British Security Industry Association, on the number of attacks against security officers; further notes with concern that many security officers injured in attacks receive no sick pay, counselling or welfare support from their employers; believes that security officers attacked on duty should not suffer financially, and urges employers in the security industry to implement sick pay and injury on duty schemes; and calls on all companies in the security industry, clients using the services of security companies, security industry trade associations, hon. Members, the Government, local authorities and others to sign up to and endorse GMB's SafeGuard Charter, and thus commit to taking action to reduce the number of attacks on security officers, to improve training and terms and conditions of employment in the security industry, and to ensure that security officers are treated with dignity and respect.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2010 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1015.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate Change (Sectoral Targets) Bill </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/851.htm</link>
			<description>That this House welcomes the provisions of the Climate Change (Sectoral Targets) Bill introduced on 9 February 2010 by the hon. Member for Gower, which would require the Secretary of State to set long-term targets for energy efficiency in the domestic and non-domestic sectors, for renewable energy, for microgeneration and for other low carbon sources of energy generation in order to satisfy all of the UK's energy needs, provide for security of supply and also help achieve carbon reduction targets; notes that the Bill would also require a strategy to be drawn up and implemented by the Secretary of State in order to achieve those targets; and believes that such an approach will provide an immediate, flexible, realistic and cost-effective way of delivering the stated objectives of energy policy which would also create jobs and help regenerate the economy.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/851.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mandatory Standards For The Quality Of Food Served In Nurseries </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1041.htm</link>
			<description>That this House is aware that the younger the child, the more vulnerable their health to the effects of poor quality food and nutrition; is alarmed that more than one in every five children starts school already overweight or obese and that this makes them more likely to suffer from serious health problems later in life; notes that existing regulation for food served in early years daycare is inadequate and does not prohibit the serving of foods high in salt, fat, sugar and artificial additives that are prohibited or restricted in primary and secondary schools; is concerned that nursery catering staff are not required to undertake training in nutrition; and calls on the Secretary of State for Children, Schools and Families to follow the Soil Association's Better Nursery Food Now campaign recommendations to implement mandatory standards for the quality of food served in all nurseries.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1041.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>World Tuberculosis Day </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1072.htm</link>
			<description>That this House recognises the importance of World Tuberculosis Day on 24 March 2010; notes with concern the continued rise in tuberculosis (TB) cases globally, resulting in nearly 5,000 deaths a day and the increase of TB in the UK, particularly among vulnerable, marginalised populations; further notes that TB-HIV co-infection and TB drug resistance is fuelling the epidemic; and calls on the Government to ensure the maximum effectiveness is achieved through its efforts in the UK and overseas to combat this preventable and curable disease.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1072.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Uprating Of State Earnings-Related Pensions </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1040.htm</link>
			<description>That this House supports measures introduced for the support of pensioners; welcomes the impact that the 2010 pensions uprating will have adding 2.5 per cent. to the basic pension; but expresses its concern about the decision to freeze state earnings-related pensions; calls on the Chancellor of the Exchequer to use the Budget statement to ensure that the 2.5 per cent. uprating also applies to state earnings-related pensions; and believes that such a move would be widely welcomed and that it would further demonstrate the Government's continued commitment to providing support to pensioners.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2010 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1040.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Robin Hood Tax Campaign </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/913.htm</link>
			<description>That this House supports the Robin Hood tax campaign which calls for the introduction of a financial transaction tax; notes that by taking an average of 0.05 per cent. from speculative banking transactions, hundreds of billions of pounds could be raised every year to tackle poverty and climate change, at home and abroad; believes that banks, which had a large role in causing the economic crisis, should do more than just pay back the bailouts or insure against future crises; further believes that a Robin Hood tax would be an effective and popular response, with a recent poll finding that 80 per cent. of respondents supported the introduction of a Robin Hood tax; commends the work of all those organisations backing this campaign who have mobilised their supporters to increase the pressure for such change; believes that this tax is an idea that has come of age; and urges the Government to do all possible to ensure that the Robin Hood tax becomes a reality.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/913.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>World Kidney Day 2010 </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1064.htm</link>
			<description>That this House welcomes World Kidney Day 2010 which raises awareness of kidney disease among the general population and seeks to publicise the link between kidney disease and diabetes; is alarmed that kidney disease is common and increasing; notes that diabetic kidney disease remains the single most common cause of renal failure; further notes that kidney failure and diabetes can lead to an elevated risk of heart disease; further welcomes the introduction of the NHS Health Check which supports the early detection of kidney disease; urges the Government to build upon these measures through a public health campaign highlighting the importance of kidneys; applauds the efforts of kidney patients, their families and friends, clinicians and healthcare professionals who have worked hard to highlight the issues associated with kidney disease and spread the important message of World Kidney Day; expresses its concern that an estimated 13,000 people die from kidney disease annually in this country; further notes that in the UK numbers of adults receiving dialysis treatment for kidney failure is increasing every year by eight per cent.; strongly believes that patient choice is the key to ensuring the best possible quality of life for patients; and calls on the Government to investigate ways by which to improve levels of patient choice in renal services.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2010 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1064.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mutuals Manifesto </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1042.htm</link>
			<description>That this House welcomes the publication of the Mutuals Manifesto; supports the Manifesto's commitment to more businesses belonging to their customers, more community-led public services and more employee-owned firms; further notes that the nature of the recession has raised fundamental questions about how businesses are owned and the economy is structured; and calls on the Government to support and encourage the mutual sector and the aims of the Manifesto.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1042.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Cycling And The Vote Bike Manifesto Campaign </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1009.htm</link>
			<description>That this House notes the benefits of cycling to health and to communities, streets and the environment; welcomes the substantial recent increases in cycle use in London and other parts of Britain including several of the Cycle Towns; and supports the aims of the Vote Bike manifesto to make cycling mainstream by strengthening the political and resource commitments made to cycling by Government departments, local authorities, health and other relevant bodies, improving the training and skills of planners and engineers required to deliver quality cycle-friendly planning and design, tackling the risks faced by cyclists through training and awareness campaigns for both drivers and cyclists through lower speed limits and through strengthened road traffic law and enforcement, enhancing provision for combining cycling with public transport by ensuring good access to stations and interchanges, providing secure parking including cycle hubs at major stations and sensibly managed provision for carrying cycles on public transport, providing encouragement, incentives and opportunities to try out cycling in schools and workplaces and for key target groups such as health patients and disadvantaged groups, plus tax incentives to support the use, purchase and repair of cycles and related accessories, and creating new and improved opportunities for recreational and off-road cycling including the appropriate opening up of green spaces, forest land, rights of way, waterways and sections of Britain's coast in order to deliver substantial increases in cycle use while halving the risks of cycling within 10 years.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2010 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1009.htm</guid>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>