<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0">
<channel>
	<title>Most Recent Early Day Motions</title>
	<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/</link>
	<description>Monitor the most recently proposed Early Day Motions</description>
	<language>en-gb</language>
	<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2010 07:02:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<ttl>10</ttl>
		<item>
			<title>UK Engineering Manifesto </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1139.htm</link>
			<description>That this House commends the Institution of Mechanical Engineers' manifesto for UK engineering; recognises that engineering is integral to the UK's national economy and environment; urges the Government to take note of the proposals in the manifesto; and calls on the Government to put a regenerated UK manufacturing sector at the heart of its agenda.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1139.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Interest Free Credit </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1138.htm</link>
			<description>That this House believes that HM Treasury should alleviate the effects of the recession and prevent the continued escalation of debt by matching the amount of money created through quantitative easing by the Bank of England with interest free cash for financing works in the public interest, thus addressing the enormous imbalance between interest bearing credit and interest free cash in the overall money supply.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1138.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Supermarkets And Community Investment </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1137.htm</link>
			<description>That this House is deeply concerned at the monopolistic influence of the major supermarkets and their effect on communities and independent retailers; and calls for a five per cent. tax to be levied on the turnover of supermarkets and for the revenue from this to be made available to local social enterprises, charities and third sector organisations.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1137.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rape Of The Fair Country Film Campaign </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1136.htm</link>
			<description>That this House encourages the campaign of historian Chris Barber to produce a film of Alexander Cordell's classic story The Rape of the Fair Country; applauds the enduring truth of Cordell's revelation of the harrowing injustices of working life in the nineteenth century; and believes that new generations should be informed of the value of political heroism in creating a fair and compassionate society.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1136.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Confidence In Parliament And Parliamentarians </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1135.htm</link>
			<description>That this House, recognising the vital importance of hon. Members in protecting and supporting constituents, defending and advancing constituencies, serving their parties and controlling the executive and considering that the great majority of hon. Members work hard and face considerable strain for pay lower than most comparable occupations, and further seeing that the standing of Parliament and its members has been deeply damaged by the clamorous campaign whipped up by sections of the media who want to arrogate to themselves Parliament's job of controlling the executive, leading the political debate and articulating the grievances of the people and further recognising that this campaign has been facilitated by the failures of the Fees Office, the ineptness of the Kelly and Legg reviews and the failure of party leaders to defend and sustain their rank and file members, urges hon. Members, as this Parliament draws to a close, not to be cast down by the populist clamour and the lack of respect that this maelstrom of misunderstanding which this has led to, but urges them to bear the slings and arrows of outrageous politics with magnanimity in order to maintain confidence in their work and value, and to go forth with confidence wherever their destiny now calls them whether to a happy retirement, a new and less stressful job, or to renew their bonds with their constituents in the coming election, congratulates them all on the sterling but insufficiently appreciated good service they have performed in this Parliament, and wishes them hail and farewell.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1135.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>State Funding For Faith And Secular Organisations </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1134.htm</link>
			<description>That this House notes that the Government has announced a £50,000 fund for a prize to uncover and reward the best examples of faith projects and a £1 million fund which national representative faith bodies can bid for to support them in developing their capacity to engage with Government, and play their part in delivering public services; further notes that a majority of the population in the UK neither practices nor adheres to any religion; and therefore calls upon the Government to fund secular groups for similar purposes to at least a matching level, or withdraw taxpayer funding for these projects altogether.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1134.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Port Rates And The Valuation Office Agency </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1133.htm</link>
			<description>That this House is concerned that the Valuation Office Agency, having failed to fulfil its responsibility to separately assess and list port companies in 2005 because it got 600 wrong and missed another 700 altogether, is now imposing the consequences of its own incompetence on the companies by massive demands for retrospective rates; considers that no government agency should have the draconian powers to impose huge retrospective charges out of the blue and acknowledges that the consequences will be job and investment losses, insolvencies and major costs on Britain's ports; calls on the Chancellor of the Exchequer to cancel these retrospective demands before local authorities are required to begin recovery proceedings; recognises that the companies have already been paying business rates through the cumulo rented system and should not be charged double taxation; and further calls on the Government to accept that any other course of action is unjust, unfair, deeply damaging and ruinous for the affected ports.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1133.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Celebration Of St Patrick's Day In Montserrat </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1132.htm</link>
			<description>That this House joins the people of the British Overseas Territory of Montserrat in celebrating St Patrick's Day on 17 March 2010; recognises the shared heritage and special relationship between the peoples of the UK and Montserrat that date back to Christopher Columbus's epic journey in 1493; notes the resilient nature of those living on the Emerald Island of the Caribbean in recovering and prospering following the eruption of the Soufriere Hills Volcano in 1997; and calls on the Government to continue to strengthen the close constitutional, economic and cultural ties that bind the peoples of Montserrat and the United Kingdom together, as well as cherishing the shared bond represented by Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II as Head of State and Sovereign.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1132.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Use Of Mephedrone </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1131.htm</link>
			<description>That this House notes with concern the recent death of two teenagers after taking the legal drug mephedrone, otherwise known as m-cat or meow-meow; further notes that mephedrone is widely available on the internet at a cost much lower than that of illegal drugs such as cocaine and that many more deaths may occur due to this combination of low cost and wide availability; further notes that little research has been done into the long-term effects of this drug; and calls on the Government to bring forward plans to outlaw the use and possession of mephedrone as a matter of urgency.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1131.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Retro-Reflective Markings And Heavy Goods Vehicles </title>
			<link>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1130.htm</link>
			<description>That this House notes that the rate of fatal accidents involving heavy goods vehicles (HGVs) remains disproportionately high, causing 75 per cent. of all road fatalities despite accounting for only 5.6 per cent. of UK road traffic; recognises that retro-reflective markings along the side and rear of HGVs have been proved to be an effective means of reducing accidents, improving safety for hauliers and all other road users; applauds Reflect for its work on promoting the benefits of these markings; and calls on all haulage companies to sign up to a voluntary code of practice to fit retro-reflective markings on HGVs, prior to it becoming mandatory for newly-registered vehicles in June 2011.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.edms.org.uk/edms/2009-2010/1130.htm</guid>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>